♪The night wind shakes off
the withered leaves♪
♪I open the window and gaze at the moon♪
♪Haze spreads across the river,
lanterns drifting♪
♪I hear the memories rustling♪
♪Garden flowers shed petals one by one♪
♪Candlelight flickers,
swaying with melancholy♪
♪I sigh by the lamp over the long night♪
♪Past memories unfold scene by scene♪
♪It's all your face♪
♪Boldly trampling over my heart♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for love miswritten♪
♪And another for youth passed♪
♪With endless sorrow,
I once traced your silhouette♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for joy and sorrow♪
♪And another for parting and reunion♪
♪I write until splendor fades,
and I am no more♪
=Prelude of the White Snake=
=Episode 24=
You and I have always been one.
Now my time has come to an end.
You are right.
This is the retribution I must bear.
Suddenly, I miss the days
we used to drink together.
You could always outdrink me.
As the Diamond Sutra says,
"The past mind cannot be grasped,
the present mind cannot be grasped,
and the future mind cannot be grasped."
What's past
has faded away,
and the future is nothing
but a castle in the air.
Better seize the present
and cherish the one before you.
Fahai.
Xu Xian.
Suzhen.
I wonder
if you've passed your love trial.
Hang in there.
I'll heal you right now.
Xu Xian.
It's useless.
When winter comes,
I won't be able to hold you anymore.
Next time, it'll be my turn
to hold the umbrella for you.
It's a promise.
You can't break it.
Xu Xian.
Abbot Fahai,
how do you interpret this fortune stick?
(Stick 14)
Keep kindness in your heart,
walk the righteous path,
and you will reach the other shore.
Madam has given birth!
It's a boy!
How is my wife?
Everything's fine.
Have you thought of a name?
Not yet.
Father, how about naming him Xu Xian?
(Xu Xian? Why Xu Xian?)
May I ask your name, Miss?
Bai Suzhen.
I am Xu Xian.
I wonder how to repay your kindness.
Just do as the storybooks said,
marry me in return.
A person like me
doesn't deserve a happy match.
I spent all my savings
to buy that house for you.
Now, I can't even afford an inn.
I'm staying at your place.
I don't deserve your kindness.
Please leave.
We've spent so much time together,
a man and a woman alone in a room.
Word gets out, bad for your name.
Why do you keep criticizing me?
Don't you care if I got hurt?
Well, are you hurt?
♪Having loved you so deep,
how could I love another♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
Does it look good?
Yes.
Bow to heaven and earth.
Since we have drunk the nuptial wine,
we are a real married couple now.
♪I'll lock you away and set myself free♪
Though I didn't do it,
they did die because of me.
I'm sorry.
(Xu Xian, I'm sorry.)
I don't expect your forgiveness,
but I hope you can let go
of your obsession with revenge.
Suzhen, you've underestimated
how much you mean to Xu Xian.
When your evil self
trapped you in the mural,
(Xu Xian was the first
to notice something was wrong.)
(He also risked his life)
(to save you
with the Du'e Ancient Scroll.)
The injuries on him were from saving me?
(Since you need me for your trial,)
(then I'll use you once too.)
(From now on, I need you)
(by my side at all times.)
(Without my permission,)
you can't take one step away from me.
Can you really bear
to walk away like this?
What about your love trial?
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
♪I shouldn't have been so foolish
to think there was still hope♪
♪But you won't even admit what we had♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
Suzhen,
I've finally taken human form.
Qing,
will you return
to the mortal realm with me
to go through my unfinished trial?
Wherever you go, I'll follow.
♪Having ever loved♪
♪I also gave my youth to someone♪
♪I must admit, you made the journey♪
♪When loving you
became instinct, what's left♪
♪Seals a fate too brutal to amend♪
♪Clumsy and new, we gave our first kiss♪
♪Never thought passionate eyes
would turn cold♪
♪I thought of pulling away,
but I'd barely begun♪
♪Having loved you so deep,
how could I love another♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
♪I shouldn't have been so foolish
to think there was still hope♪
♪But you won't even admit what we had♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I have questions,
I never questioned you♪
♪I'll lock you away and set myself free♪
♪After all, I'm the one you deny♪
♪Having ever loved♪